(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T17:00:57.476347",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
うー、あー、もー、はい
Ooh, ah, mo, ready!
やだやだ ミスってらんない ね？
No way, no way, I can't afford to mess up, okay?
みんな たくさんきゅんきゅんして
Everyone, get super excited
楽しんでいってね！いくぞー！
and enjoy yourselves! Here we go!
真っ赤なハート差し出して
Holding out a bright red heart,
そんなのやっぱ妄想じゃん
that's just a delusion after all.
そっちはどう思ってなの
What are you thinking over there?
言いかけてしまう無理みたい
I almost blurted it out, seems impossible.
こんなんじゃってわかってるんだ
I know it's like this,
ハマっていくんだ 頑張りたい
falling deeper into it, I want to try my best.
あたしに期待 ぎゅーだってしたいかも… かもん？
Expecting from myself, maybe I even want a hug... c'mon?
ちょっとは変われてますか？ 足ないこばっかりだけど
Have I changed a bit? Though I'm still full of shortcomings,
ポンでコツでドジでじゃないあたしだったら きみはだめだよね？
if I were someone without clumsiness or blunders, you wouldn't want me, right?
ねぇ もう やだやだ ミスってらんない ねぇ もう
Hey, no more, no way, I can't afford to mess up, hey, no more,
やだやだ 踊ってベイビダンス あたしはまだ 諦めない
no way, dancing baby dance, I still won't give up.
でもでも 全然だめかも だってベイビダンス
But still, maybe it's totally no good, because it's a baby dance,
今うまくできないな 伝えられないな
I can't do it well right now, I can't convey it.
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいかわかんないし
Even though I want to become cuter, I don't know what to do,
やだやだ ミスってらんない ね？
no way, no way, I can't afford to mess up, okay?
あーやっちまったこんなはずじゃ
Ah, I messed up, it wasn't supposed to be like this.
どうしてどうしてわかっているのに
Why, why, even though I know,
見せたくないとこ逃げちゃって無理無理
I run away from parts I don't want to show, impossible.
でも期待をしたいのいいですか？
But is it okay to have expectations?
ポンもコツもドジも全部あたしなんだよ
Clumsiness, tricks, and blunders are all a part of me,
ちゃんと見ていてほしい ねぇ
so I want you to watch me properly, hey.
もうやだやだ ぐずって後悔もう
Already no way, no way, sulking and regretting,
やだやだ 回ってベイビダンス
no way, no way, spinning around in a baby dance,
だめなあたい塗り替えたいでも
I want to repaint this useless me, but
でも全然だめかも だってベイビダンス
but maybe it's totally no good, because it's a baby dance,
今うまくできないな 伝えられないな
I can't do it well right now, I can't convey it.
もっと可愛くなりたいのに どうしたらいいかわかんないし
Even though I want to become cuter, I don't know what to do,
やだやだ ミスってらんない ね？
no way, no way, I can't afford to mess up, okay?
まだまだいけるかな まだまだ言えるかな まだまだできるかな まだまだ… うう…
Can I still go on? Can I still say it? Can I still do it? Still... ooh...
ポンでコツでドジでだめですでに足りないこばっかりだって きっとやめないんだ
Clumsy, awkward, full of flaws and not enough, but I'm definitely not going to stop.
ポンでコツでドジでだめですでに足りないこばっかりだって 見ていてほしい uh yeah~
Clumsy, awkward, full of flaws and not enough, I want you to watch me, uh yeah~
もうやだやだ ミスってらんないもう
Already no way, no way, I can't afford to mess up,
やだやだ 踊ってベイビダンス
no way, no way, dancing baby dance,
あたしはまだ 諦めない ほら
I still won't give up, hey,
ほら全然だめじゃない だってベイビダンス
hey, it's not totally no good, because it's a baby dance,
うまくできるから 伝えられるから
because I can do it well, because I can convey it.
もっと可愛くなりたいから どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし
Because I want to become cuter, no matter what time, I can do my best.
だってベイビダンス きみに届くまで だってベイビダンス きみに会えるまで
Because it's a baby dance, until it reaches you, because it's a baby dance, until I can meet you,
もっと可愛くなりたいから どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし
because I want to become cuter, no matter what time, I can do my best.
やだやだ ミスってらんない ね？
No way, no way, I can't afford to mess up, okay?
はーい！ みんなにゃはろー！
Hii! Nya-hello, everyone!
エリトミコがお送りするさくらみこでーす！
This is Sakura Miko, brought to you by Elit Miko!
さくらみこ きゅんきゅん生誕祭2024に来てくれてありがとう！ ちょっと噛んだ！
Thank you for coming to Sakura Miko's Kyun-Kyun Birthday Festival 2024! I tripped over my words!
はい、ということで、
Yes, and with that,
今回のライブはみんなをきゅんきゅんさせる可愛いライブとなております！
this concert is a cute live performance that will make everyone go kyun-kyun!
ステージも見て！可愛い！
Look at the stage too! So cute!
あのね、すごい凝ってくれました！スタッフさんありがとう！
You know, they put so much effort into it! Thank you to the staff!
めちゃくちゃ街並みが、あの、とてもね、おしゃれになっております！可愛い！
The cityscape has become, um, very fashionable! So cute!
そして、ハッシュタグはこちら！さくらみこ生誕祭でたくさん呟いてね！
And the hashtag is right here! Tweet a lot with #SakuraMikoBirthday!
お楽しみにしていてくださいね！
Please look forward to it!
後半にはなんと可愛い新衣装もあるのね！
And in the second half, there's even a cute new outfit!
最後まで絶対みんな見逃すなよ！
Make sure everyone watches till the very end!
それでは、次はゲストパートです！行くぞー！
Now then, next is the guest part! Let's go!
ねね！ねぇねぇ！あの人たちねねたちのこと見てない？
Nene! Hey, hey! Aren't those people looking at us?
いや、ねねのことだけ見てるかも～♡
Nope, maybe they're only looking at Nene~♡
いやいやいやいや、勘違いすんなってぇ！みこの事見てるもん！
No no no no, don't misunderstand! They're looking at Miko!
はいはい～おこちゃまは黙ってな～！
Yeah, yeah~ little kids should stay quiet~!
ねぇねぇ、ねねといっしょにあそぶ？
Hey hey, wanna play with Nene?
みことあそぶよね？
You'll play with Miko, right?
なんでいつも素っ気ないのよ、クール気取っちゃって
Why are you always so cold, acting all cool?
会いたいんでしょ？恋しいんでしょ？素直になろうよ！
You want to see me, right? You miss me, right? Be honest!
それなら君の気を引いちゃうもん！ドキドキ溢れる大作戦♡
If so, I'll catch your attention! A heart-pounding grand operation♡
1分2分3分4分LINEも未読スルーするんだ
1 minute, 2 minutes, 3 minutes, 4 minutes, even leaving my LINE messages unread.
「最近なんか気になって仕方ないんだよな…」
"Lately I've been so obsessed, I can't help it..."
そんな感じで毎晩ずっと何度も何度もきっとSNSしちゃうでしょ？
Like that every single night, over and over, you'll definitely check your SNS, right?
ほら、もっと夢中になって！ (>_<)♡
Come on, get even more obsessed! (>_<)♡
わざとあけたこのストーリー 君の足跡チェックするの
This story I posted on purpose, I'm checking your views.
あざといなんて言わないで だってLove you Love you Love youキラッ✨
Don't call me calculating, because Love you Love you Love you, sparkle✨
わざと遅い既読通知 私の心 非公開
Deliberately delayed read receipts, my heart is private.
鍵をかけた恋心
A lock put on my romantic feelings.
ねえほらほらほら 私を気にして
Hey, come on, come on, pay attention to me!
私の声で君が笑うから
Because you smile at my voice,
その瞬間も切り取って即保存しちゃいたい
I want to capture that exact moment and save it instantly.
そのために心奪っちゃいます
That's why I'll steal your heart.
明日は君の誕生日 5分4分3分2分
Tomorrow is your birthday, 5 minutes, 4 minutes, 3 minutes, 2 minutes.
「おめでとう！」わざと早まって
"Happy birthday!" deliberately jumping the gun.
「ごめん、誰より早く伝えたかったんだ」
"Sorry, I wanted to tell you before anyone else."
そんなこと言えばあっという間チョコレートみたい溶けちゃうね
If I say something like that, in a flash, it'll melt like chocolate.
もう！早く振り向いて！ (^o^)♡
Geez! Turn around already! (^o^)♡
わざとあざとエキスパート 私の心 のぞいてよ
Waza to Azato Expert, peek into my heart!
タイムラインは君ばっかもっとLove you Love you Love you キュン！ドキドキチュウ！君だけに限定公開
My timeline is all about you, more Love you, limited release just for you.
足跡つくの待ってるのに
Even though I'm waiting for your footprints to appear,
このままいけばログアウト そんなのやだやだやだ
If it stays like this, I'll log out. No way, no way, no way!
私を愛してずっとずっと
Love me, forever and ever.
やっと見れた君のアカウントも
The account of yours I finally got to see,
やっぱ君も私を好きなんだね
Turns out you like me too, huh?
わざとは全部君のためなんだから
All this calculating is all for your sake,
落ちちゃえばいいんだ
So you might as well just fall for me.
だけど私少し反省 あまり試すの良くないね
But I'm reflecting a little, testing you too much isn't good.
やけに遅い既読通知 やっぱ気になる！なる！
Unusually delayed read receipts, I still care! I do!
わざとあけたこのストーリー 君の足跡チェックするの
This story I posted on purpose, I'm checking your views.
あざといなんて言わないで だってLove you Love you Love you 好きだっちゃ！
Don't call me calculating, because Love you Love you Love you, I love you!
わざと遅い既読通知 私の心非公開 鍵をかけた恋心
Deliberately delayed read receipts, my heart is private, a lock put on my romantic feelings.
ねえほらほらほら 私を気にして
Hey, come on, come on, pay attention to me!
もっともっと まさか君もわざとなの？
More and more, could it be that you were doing it on purpose too?
「みこち、お誕生日おめでとう！」
"Mikochi, happy birthday!"
「ねねちありがとね！」 「祝いだよ～！」 「ライブ誘ってくれてありがとうね！嬉しいよ！」
"Neneci, thanks!" "It's a celebration~!" "Thanks for inviting me to the live! I'm so happy!"
「うんうん、これからもずっとやろうね！」
"Yeah yeah, let's keep doing this forever!"
ちょっとちょっとみこ先輩！
Wait a minute, Miko-senpai!
こないだお祝い酒だって お酒飲みすぎなんですよぉ！
You drank way too much saying it was celebration sake the other day!
え～ そんなにみこの生誕祭が嬉しいのかなぁ～？
Eh~ Are you really that happy about Miko's birthday celebration~?
あっ、めちゃくちゃ首振ってますよぉ！
Ah, you're shaking your head like crazy!
こらぁ、ツンデレかぁ～？
Hey now, are you being a tsundere~?
こういうときは素直にならんかぁいっ！
You should just be honest at times like this!
そうだそうだぁ～、ラミィたんいいこと言うなァ～！
That's right, that's right~, Lamy-tan, you've got a good point~!
おい、あれぇ～、ん？ちょっと！聞いてんのかァ～！
Hey, wait a second~, hmm? Hey! Are you listening~?!
お願いしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me.
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も 毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
I told you so much to stop smoking and drinking—two packs and seven cans every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても 看護してあげないんだから
Even if your liver gets ruined and you're done for, I won't nurse you!
ああ言えばこう言う てことできかない あなたのハートは真っ黒です
You have a comeback for every remark, and your heart is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You won't say what you want to say,
行きたいところからやりたいことまで 決めてるくせしてだんまりさん
yet you decide everything from where to go to what to do, acting like Mr. Silence!
ねぇ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, isn't that like an idiot?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
いつも思わせぶりな感じで 察してほしい感じで
Always playing hard to get, wanting me to guess,
わざと口にしないの ずるくない？
not saying it on purpose—isn't that unfair?
馬鹿じゃないの？
Aren't you an idiot?
お願い ダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look at me, listen.
欲しいのは 形のないもの
What I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて
I won't make fun of you, look at me, listen,
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
peek deep into my eyes.
真っ直ぐ 見つめて
Gazing straight ahead,
お願いしてみて 欲しいの
I want you to pester me.
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all!
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷりって
I gazed at you so gallantly, yet now you're completely pretending not to know!
ていうかそれって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないですか？ぶっちゃけ
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels? To be honest,
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです
thanks to your smooth talk, my heart is all worn out!
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold,
そっちが中々言い出さないから いつも私が勝ち取りじゃん？
and since you never speak up, I'm always the one taking charge, right?
ねぇ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, isn't this somewhat stupid?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
どこか足元見てる感じで
Feeling like you're appraising me from below,
舐め見されてる感じで
feeling like I'm being looked down on—
駆け引きやろうか勝ち負けじゃなくない？
isn't this supposed to be about tactics, not winning or losing?
そういうめんどくさいことしてるから めんどくさいことになるんだよ
You do such annoying things, that's why it ends up being so annoying!
寡黙な ダーリン ねぇ聞いて
Silent darling, hey, listen,
切なさは 飾りじゃないのよ
pain isn't a decoration.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで
Don't look away, don't run away,
触ってよ 心の奥の方
touch deep in my heart.
一瞬の ことじゃない
This isn't just a momentary thing!
お願い ダーリン してはくれないの？
Please, darling, won't you pester me?
言葉に出来ない奥病さは 強さではないのよ
The cowardice you can't put into words isn't strength!
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Don't just be spoiled, express yourself!
もう ちゃんとこっち向いてってば！
Jeez, look this way properly!
お願い ダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look at me, listen.
欲しいのは 形のないもの
What I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて
I won't make fun of you, look at me, listen,
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
peek deep into my eyes.
寡黙な ダーリン 逃げないで
Silent darling, don't run away,
甘えてよ 私の素顔を
show my true face as you cuddle up to me!
お願い ダーリン そばにいて
Please, darling, stay by my side,
触らせて 心の奥の方
let me touch deep in your heart.
真っ直ぐ 見つめて
Gazing straight ahead,
お願いしてみて 欲しいの
I want you to pester me.
お願いダーリン！
Please, darling!
みこ先輩 お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Miko-senpai, happy birthday!
みたーい！ありがとう！
Lamy-tan, thank you!
はぁ… 誕生日なのに…
Haah… Even though it's my birthday…
どんなにみんなにお祝いされても 結局部屋で一人なんだよなぁ。
No matter how much everyone celebrates with me, in the end, I'm all alone in my room.
バーチャルって… あれ？ かなたんからLINEだ。
Virtual is… Huh? It's a LINE message from Kanatan.
みこてんぱい、なに寂しがってるんですか？ かなたそがいるじゃん！
Miko-tempai, why are you feeling lonely? Kanataso is right here!
わかるよその気持ち、だから… かなたそがなんでも聞いてあげるよ…？
I understand how you feel, so… Kanataso will listen to anything you have to say…?
かなたん…！♡
Kanatan…! ♡
インターネットエンジェルという現象は
The phenomenon known as the internet angel
規定された有機交流電灯の
is the lighting of prescribed organic communication lamps,
かわいい虹色の照明です
cute rainbow-colored illumination.
あらゆる透明なアカンの複合体
Every kind of transparent composite of Akans,
クソゴミカス キショキショな現実を忘れさせてあげる
trash scum, making you forget the gross reality—
チャンネル登録者百万人のみんなには内緒だぞ
it's a secret to all one million subscribers!
大丈夫もう何も怖くないからこんなSNS抜け出して二人で海に見に行くぞ！
It's okay, nothing's scary anymore, so let's escape this SNS and go see the ocean together!
インターネット・やめろ！
Internet Yamero!
INTERNET YAMERO
インターネット・エンジェルという 現象 は
An internet angel phenomenon...
わかる真似をして なにも知らないね
With no time to even catch my breath, I've been running through.
アナタ
You pretend to understand.
なにが悲しいの なにが寂しいの 聴こえてる？
What is sadness? What is loneliness? Can you hear me?
人が恋しくて 人がイヤすぎて ループ
You love people's warmth yet you hate people so much, it's a loop.
夜が好きなのに 一人じゃ寒くて 震えてる
You like the night yet you shiver alone in the cold...
本当は幸せを知っているのに 不不幸なフリ やめられないね
To be honest, I know what happiness is, yet I can't stop pretending to be unhappy.
アンチに負けず 信者に媚びず
Don't lose to the haters, don't pander to believers.
どんなに努力を重ねても
No matter how much effort you put in,
一瞬先は地獄行き
you're one step away from hell.
いやもうすでに冥府魔道
No, I'm already in the path of the netherworld.
地獄の沙汰もいいね次第
Hell's affairs depend on likes.
偽善者トラップ 蜘蛛の糸
Hypocrite's trap, spider's thread.
こんなに苦しいはずなのに
Even though it should be so painful,
インターネットがやめられないない！発狂！
I can't stop using the internet! Going crazy!
かけめぐるエクスタシー 融けるマイスリー
Ecstasy running through me, melting my myslee.
画面光りだすの 不安止まらないよ
The screen starts shining, anxiety won't stop.
誰か殺してくれ イヤマだ 死にたくない
Someone kill me, no I don't want to die.
朝は見たくないの
I don't want to see the morning.
ムリだ！死ぬ！頭割れてく――！
It's impossible! I'm dying! My head is splitting!
それでもわたしはこのカオスをオタクと歩む ここにしかない光景を見つけに行くから
Even so, I will walk through this chaos with my nerds to find a sight that can only be found here.
あんなにおそろしい 乱れたインターネットから この雪みたいに美しい毒電波がきたんだよ
From that terrifying, chaotic internet, poisonous radio waves as beautiful as snow came down.
カウンセリングを受けたの
I went to get counseling.
先生から「ネットをやめろ」って言われて
The doctor told me to "stop using the internet."
もうおまえらと会えないと思った瞬間 胸が苦しくて リアルが壊れてもここが良いと思ったの
The moment I thought I would never see you guys again, my chest hurt so much, thinking this place was better even if reality breaks.
初めてフォローされた日のこと覚えてる？ もう細かいことはどうでもいいね せーのっ
I remember the day I got my first follower, and how minor details don't matter anymore, ready, go!
インターネット最高！！！
Internet is the best!
ほとばしるエクスタシー 甘い夢を見せてマイスリー
Gushing ecstasy, show me a sweet dream, myslee.
指先で感じる 泳ぐ電子の海 インターネット・ボーイ
Fingers feeling it, swimming in the electronic sea, internet boy.
悲しみ舞い散る 暗い闇の中 インターネット・ゲーム
Sadness dances and scatters in the dark night, internet game.
アナタのとなり微笑む 忘れないでいてね インターネット・ガール きっと……
Smiling beside you, don't ever forget me, internet girl, surely...
キボンヌ！オワタ！半年ROMれ！キタ〜！age！漏れ！香具師！逝ってよし！久しぶりに笑ウタ！
Kibonnu! Owata! Half year rom-re! Kita~! Age! More! Yashi! Itte yoshi! Hisabisa ni warouta!
ぽまいら！これはおつじゃなくてポニーテールなんだからね！
Pomaira! This isn't otsu, it's a ponytail!
ブヒヒ！ぬるぽ！禿同！
Buhihi! Nurupo! Hagedou!
無理ぽ！おまえもな！俺愛は三行！アップしる！
Muripo! Omaemona! Oreai wa sangyou! Up shiru!
日本語でおk！一の母です！
Nihongo de ookei! Ichi no haha desu!
キボンヌ！オワタ！半年ROMれ！キタ〜！age！漏れ！禿同！
Kibonnu! Owata! Half year rom-re! Kita~! Age! More! Hagedou!
すきすきすきすきすきすきすきすき
Suki suki suki suki...
青白いモニター越しの光を通し オタクの孤独を癒やして回る
Through the light across the pale monitor, healing the loneliness of nerds,
わたしはインターネットの天使なのだ
I am the angel of the internet!
ういちゃぁ〜ん、へへへ。
Ui-chaaaan, hehehe...
かわいいねぇ〜、ちっちゃいねぇ〜……
So cute, so small~~
キモイですよ、みこおねーちゃん^^
That's creepy, Miko-oneechan.
お誕生日なのに警察にいきたいんですかぁ？ そんなこといってぇ〜、みことお祝いに来てくれたくせに〜
You're going to a police station on your birthday? Come on, don't say that when you came to celebrate my birthday!
はぁぁ、まっ、一年警察のお世話にならないといいですね。
Well, I hope you don't get involved with the police this year.
lonely ロリロリ神、降臨 鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Lonely loli-loli god, descends. Ring the bell and this is the way.
これは救済のレクイエム
This is the requiem of salvation.
せーのっ 触ったら逮捕！極“chu-de”点呼(Uh!) いちにしーさんしー？
Ready, go! Touch and you're arrested! Extreme census with a kiss! One, two, three, four?
(ごめんなさい) はぁ？ごめんなさいが聞こえないー(え)
"I'm sorryyy!" "Huh? I can't hear your apology."
粛聖!! ロリ神レクイエム☆
Purification!! Loli-gami Requiem!
将来はお前なんかに出会いたくない
In the future, I don't want to be liked by someone like you!
泥水で口を洗え 法廷で会おうね
Wash your mouth out with muddy water. See you in court!
Lonely ロリ神、降臨
Lonely Loli-God Descend,
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Ring the bells down this street,
これは救済のレクイエム
This is the Requiem of Salvation!
せーのっ
Ready, set—
触ったら逮捕!
Touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♥de!点呼!(Uh!)
Goku-chu♥ de roll call! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー?(ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (Sorry~)
ハァ?(ﾟДﾟ)ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい(え~!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your "sorry"! (Eh~!)
粛聖!!ロリ神レクイエム
Holy!! Loli-God Requiem
ういちゃん!ういちゃん!
Ui-chan! Ui-chan!
待ってよういちゃん!ういちゃん!
Wait up, Ui-chan! Ui-chan!
その姿親に見せられますか?
Can you show that look to your parents?
みこちゃん!みこちゃん!
Miko-chan! Miko-chan!
かわいいよ、みこちゃん!
You're so cute, Miko-chan!
わぁ、ありがとう。お疲れ様です~^^
Waah, thank you. Good work~^^
Lonely ロリ神、降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely Loli-God, Descend (Zukkyuun!)
マジヤバ奴等に用心(ばっきゅーん)
Watch out for the real dangerous scum (Bakkyuun!)
まともじゃないなら 早く消えてください
If you're not decent, disappear quickly!
lonely ロリ神、降臨(ずっきゅーん!)
Lonely Loli-God, Descend (Zukkyuun!)
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り(yes!)
Ring the bells down this street (Yes!)
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a gentle and wonderful big brother
楽園でホラ ねんねしな
Sleep tight in paradise, come on
ほら。世の中には、こんなに気持ち悪い人たちが
Hey, in this world, such creepy people
蔓延しているんですっ!みんな、晒しageますよ。
are rampant! Everyone, let's air them out!
(ういちゃん...うい、こっち向いてぇ~~~)
(Ui-chan... Ui-, look this way~~~!)
触ったら逮捕!
Touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♥de!点呼!(Uh!)
Goku-chu♥ de roll call! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー?(ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (Sorry~)
ハァ?(ﾟДﾟ)ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい(え~!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your "sorry"! (Eh~!)
粛聖!!ロリ神レクイエム
Holy!! Loli-God Requiem
はぁーい、獄中にいるみなしゃーん
Haaai, to everyone in the deep prison
刑務所ファンミーティングのお時間でーす
It's Prison Fan Meeting time~!
その腐りきった耳をゴリゴリかポジって よく聴いてくださいね
Gourily grind those rotted ears and listen closely, okay?
キモキモ(助かる~ゥ)
Gross (Help~)
うるさい(助かる~ゥ)
Noisy (Help~)
黙ってもらっていてもいいですか?
Will you please shut up?
嫌いです(助かる~ゥ)
I hate it (Help~)
かわいそ(助かる~ゥ)
How pathetic (Help~)
どうしようもない お兄ちゃんお姉ちゃん
You hopeless older brothers and older sisters,
もう希望もない ゴミだおめーら
You're just hopeless pieces of trash!
汚物消毒 110番
Filth Disinfection 110
固有結界は・つ・ど・う♥
Our Territory is Ma-tsu-do♥
粛聖!!ロリ神レクイエム
Holy!! Loli-God Requiem
触ったら逮捕!
Touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♥de!点呼!(Uh!)
Goku-chu♥ de roll call! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー?(ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (Sorry~)
ハァ?(ﾟДﾟ)ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい(え~!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your "sorry"! (Eh~!)
粛聖!!ロリ神レクイエム
Holy!! Loli-God Requiem
待ってなんで誕生日ういビーム弾かれてるんぞ
Wait, why is birthday Ui-beam being blocked?
みこ自分で撃て!ビーマ自分て撃て!
Miko, shoot your own! Miko, shoot your own!
まあ誕生日やから許したるか
Well, it's her birthday, so I'll forgive her!
あぁ、あぁ...
Aah, aah...
この世の醜さを
Gathering the ugliness of this world,
集めて描いてみるよ
I try to draw it all out.
真っ白なキャンパスが 汚れで泣いている
The pure white canvas is crying, stained with filth.
Lonely 振り向いた少女は そっと手を掴む...
Lonely, the looking-back girl softly takes my hand...
『楽園など無いから』
"Because there is no paradise"
おっきなお友達のみんへ
To all you big friends out there,
お前らが打ち込んでいる虚無には、何の意味があるの?
What's the point of the emptiness you're sinking into?
ねえ、教えてよ。みこはぜんぜーんわかんないんだ!
Hey, teach me, Miko has no idea at all!
ロリロリ神、降臨
Lonely Loli-God, Descend
さよなら笑顔でバイバイ
Sayonara, smile, bye-bye
ピリオドどうぞ この手で押してあげゆ
Period, here you go, push it with this hand!
ロリロリ神、降臨
Lonely Loli-God, Descend
鐘を鳴らせばこの通り
Ring the bells down this street
とても優しくて 素敵なお兄ちゃん
Such a gentle and wonderful big brother
楽園でホラ ねんねしな
Sleep tight in paradise, come on
それが救済の
That is the salvation...
レクイエム
Requiem.
せーのっ 触ったら逮捕!
Ready, touch me and you're arrested!
極chu♥de!点呼!(Uh!)
Goku-chu♥ de roll call! (Uh!)
いちにーさんしー?(ごめんなさーい)
One, two, three, four? (Sorry~)
ハァ?(ﾟДﾟ)ごめんなさいが、聞こえなーい(え~!)
Huh? (ﾟДﾟ) I can't hear your "sorry"! (Eh~!)
粛聖!!ロリ神レクイエム
Holy!! Loli-God Requiem
ほんとに気持ち悪い。
It really tastes awful.
みこちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう!
Miko-chan, happy birthday, congratulations!
ありがとう!ういちゃん、このあ...
Thank you! Ui-chan, this...
フブさんフブさん、
Fubu-san, Fubu-san,
なんかここ変な怖~い感じがするんですけど...
I have a weirdly scary feeling about this...
いやぁ、さすがみこさん!
Hehe, as expected of Miko-san!
巫女さんだけに、ちゃんと感じ るんだね~?
You're a shrine maiden, so you really can sense it, huh~?
ここ.. 実はばやいんですよ。
This place... is actually pretty bad.
フブさん、みこ誕生日なんですけどっ!
Fubu-san, it's Miko's birthday, you know?!
まぁまぁ白上がいるし、大丈夫ですよ!
Well, well, Shirakami is here, so it's fine!
それに...いざという時は、守ってくれる人もいますし、ねっ?
Besides... in a pinch, there are people to protect us, right?
ねぇねぇ、もしものもしもだよ?
Hey, hey, what if? What if?
私が帰り道、グリズリーに襲われたら
If I were attacked by a blizzard on my way home,
あなたならどうする?
what would you do, if it were you?
もしものもしもだよ あなたはどうする?Yeah~
What if, what if, what would you do? Yeah~
もしもね帰り道
If on my way home
グリズリーと出会って
I ran into a grizzly bear,
暗闇で目合えば
and our eyes met in the dark,
恐怖で動けないわ
I'd be too terrified to move.
震える唇で
With trembling lips,
助けてと電話したら
if I called for help,
あなたはすぐに来てくれますか?
would you come running right away?
ねえ嘘付いて あしらわないで
Hey, don't lie or brush me off.
真実なの お願い
It's the truth, I'm begging you!
パジャマだって駆けつけてね
Rush over even in your pajamas,
1秒を争うのよ
every second counts!
Yシャツに着替える間に
By the time you change into a shirt,
骨まで食べられちゃうわ
I'll be eaten down to the bones!
裸足だって駆けつけてね
Rush over even barefoot,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me,
心配でたまらなくて走り出してほしいのです
I want you to worry so much you can't help but run out!
そんな人が愛しいの
That's the kind of person I adore.
もしもね曲がり角
If on a street corner
グリズリーにぶつかり
I bumped into a grizzly bear,
物陰で向き合えば
and faced it from the shadows,
恐くて叫べないわ
I'd be too scared to scream.
怯える左手で
With a trembling left hand,
助けてとメールしたら
if I texted you for help,
あなたはすぐに見てくれますか?
would you check it right away?
ねえほっといて 片付けないで
Hey, don't just leave me be or tidy up.
本当なの 信じて
It's true, please believe me!
仕事だって駆けつけてね
Rush over even from work,
なにもかもを投げ出して
dropping everything else,
残業が終わるまでにほら丸飲みされちゃうわ
before overtime ends, I'll be swallowed whole!
どこにだって駆けつけてね
Rush over no matter where,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me,
いてもたってもいられない
you can't sit still or stand still,
取り乱してほしいのです
I want you to lose your mind.
そんな人が愛しいの
That's the kind of person I adore.
ねぇもしもし 大変大変
Hey, hello? It's an emergency!
帰り道にグリズリーがいるの
There's a grizzly bear on my way home!
助けて私 恐くて一歩も動けないよ
Help me, I'm too scared to take a step!
今すぐ来て 助けて キャーこっちに来るよ
Come right now, help—ah, it's coming this way!
私のこと見てる キャー 助けてよ
It's looking right at me! Ah, help me!
ねえ嘘付いて あしらわないで
Hey, don't lie or brush me off.
真実なの お願い
It's the truth, I'm begging you!
パジャマだって駆けつけてね
Rush over even in your pajamas,
1秒を争うのよ
every second counts!
Yシャツに着替える間に
By the time you change into a shirt,
骨まで食べられちゃうわ
I'll be eaten down to the bones!
裸足だって駆けつけてね
Rush over even barefoot,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me,
心配でたまらなくて走り出してほしいのです
I want you to worry so much you can't help but run out!
そんな人が愛しいの
That's the kind of person I adore.
あなたしかいないの
There's nobody else but you.
ありがとう
Thank you!
みこさーん! 今日はお誕生日おめでとう!
Miko-san! Happy Birthday today!
ありがとう、ふぶさん!
Thank you, Fubu-san!
グリズリーじゃないけど、キツネが食べちゃうぞー! う、う、逃げろー!
It's not a grizzly, but a fox is gonna eat you! Run away!
おめでたい! おめでたい! 超めでたい! 超めでたい!
So celebratory! So celebratory! Super celebratory! Super celebratory!
本日晴れの日 雨でも晴れ
Today is a sunny day, even if it rains it's sunny
一生に一度のエブリデイだけどやっぱり今日はスペシャル
It's a once-in-a-lifetime everyday, but today is special after all
本日の衣装は悩みませーん
I'm not worried about today's outfit!
一周回ってもシンプルだけど
Even after going around once it's simple, but
あれっ? でもやっぱ派手すぎ!?
Huh? But is it too flashy?!
来年の今は記念日
Next year right now is an anniversary
それまでは
Until then,
たくさんのもっと
more and more—
どれでもいいかたちチョッキうたかもよーしょ
Whatever's fine, shaped like a vest, a cheerful song, yo-sho!
そして大事なこと
And the most important thing,
まずはTodayをぶち上げよ？ おめでとう！
First off, let's hype up Today? Congrats!
こんなに幸せでいいのかな？
Can I really be this happy?
本当はそんなこと悩んでないけど
Not that I'm actually worried about that,
だってちょっとくらいのマイナスもなきゃ
But hey, without even a tiny bit of minus,
でも暗いにいい感じ！ おめでとう！
Still, it feels pretty good! Congrats!
こんなに幸せでいいのかな？
Can I really be this happy?
だって私自分で選んだんだから
After all, I chose this myself!
犬は駆け回り 猫はかわいいし
Dogs scamper around, cats are cute,
青い鳥は飛ぶ みんながいる！
Blue birds fly, everyone is here!
当日はケの日 普通にいい
Today is just an ordinary weekday, perfectly fine,
一生で一番ヤングな日だけど仕方ないです
The youngest day of my lifetime, but it can't be helped!
って感じで冷めてもいるよ
Feeling kind of cool and detached like that too,
サプライズのメッセージ驚くはずないって、お決まり！
A surprise message? No way I'd be shocked, that's the rule!
一昨年の今は他人で
Day before yesterday we were strangers,
これまでは たくさんもっと
Until then, more and more—
無駄かってことで恋愛とかもしちゃってね
Doing things like falling in love as if it's a waste,
だけど大事なこと 今は本当に大好きです おめでとう！
But the important thing is, right now I truly love it so much! Congrats!
こんなに幸せでいいのかな？
Can I really be this happy?
本当はそんなこと心配ないけど
Not that I'm actually worried about that,
だってちょっとくらいの試練とかもなきゃ
But hey, without even a tiny bit of trial or hardship,
でも暗いにいい感じ！
Still, it feels pretty good!
結局幸せでいいの？
In the end, is it okay to be happy?
だって私ちゃんと戦ったんだから
Because I fought properly myself!
お神輿に乗って 花火も上げて いいこと全部一度にしよう！
Let's ride the mikoshi, shoot off fireworks, and do all the good things all at once!
こんなに幸せでいいのかな？
Can I really be this happy?
本当はそんなこと悩んでないけど
Not that I'm actually worried about that,
だってちょっとくらいのマイナスもなきゃ
But hey, without even a tiny bit of minus,
でも暗いにいい感じ！
Still, it feels pretty good!
こんなに幸せでいいのです
It's okay to be this happy.
だって私自分で選んだんだから
After all, I chose this myself!
犬は駆け回り 猫はかわいいし
Dogs scamper around, cats are cute,
青い鳥は飛ぶ みんながいる最高の今に
Blue birds fly, everyone is here in this best moment right now—
おめでとう！
Congrats!
Let Have a Good time 今日はセレブレーション
Let Have a Good time, today is a celebration!
超めでたいじゃん もっとセレブレーション
Super auspicious, right? More celebration!
猫になって甘えたいよ 猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be spoiled, I want to become a cat and be loved!
猫になってお昼寝させて 起きたら100万登録いってないかな
Let me take a catnap, and when I wake up, I wonder if I've hit 1 million subscribers?
猫ならばいける！
If I'm a cat, I can do it!
二度寝したいけどちゃんと おはようツイートしなく茶
I want to go back to sleep, but I gotta post a proper good morning tweet,
下書き悩んで3時間たって 完璧な140字 操作ミスってデリート
Spent 3 hours agonizing over the draft, wrote a perfect 140 characters, then mistyped and deleted it!
心が折れる日曜日
A Sunday where my spirit breaks.
心が折れそうな日曜日
A Sunday when my heart feels like breaking,
休みもなしで歌い続ける
Continuing to sing without a day off,
そんなのへっちゃら余裕だぜ
That's no big deal, I've got this!
みんなと一緒なら大丈夫
If I'm together with everyone, it'll be fine!
だから応援よろしくね
So please support me!
本質的に甘やかして
Essentially, spoil me rotten,
配信も全部見てね
And watch all my streams!
でも今日はやばい
But today is terrible...
本当にねむい
I'm really sleepy.
こんなわたしもちゃんと見てほしい
I want you to look at me properly even like this,
無償の愛がほしい
I want unconditional love.
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be spoiled!
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved!
猫になっておひるねさせて
I want to become a cat and take a nap,
起きたら100万登録だ
When I wake up, it's 1 million subs!
猫になって輝きたいの
I want to become a cat and shine!
猫になって開拓するよ
I want to become a cat and pioneer!
もっと君に伝わりますように
May it reach you even more.
お散歩してたら公園でかわいいワンちゃん見つけたよ
Walking in the park, I found a cute doggy.
撫でようとしたら吠えられた
When I tried to pet it, it barked at me.
やっぱ猫になりたい
I guess I want to be a cat after all.
でもどうすればいい？猫のなり方
But what should I do? How to become a cat:
ググっても出ない本出してほしい
Publish a book on it that even Google doesn't have!
スクール作ってほしい
I want you to build a school for it!
猫になって抱きしめられたい
I want to become a cat and be hugged!
猫になってナデナデしてよ
I want to become a cat, pet me, pet me!
猫になってエサを与えて
I want to become a cat and feed me,
山盛りチュールをよろしくね
A mountain of Churu, please!
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to become a cat and stay in love,
猫になって笑いあおうよ
I want to become a cat and laugh together!
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats even more!
本当やばい
Seriously terrible,
起きたら12時
Woke up at 12 o'clock,
LINEめちゃきてる
My LINE is overflowing.
でもまあしょうがない逆に二度寝しましょ
Oh well, can't be helped, let's sleep in instead.
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be spoiled!
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved!
猫になっておひるねさせて
I want to become a cat and take a nap,
起きたら100万登録だ
When I wake up, it's 1 million subs!
猫になって輝きたいの
I want to become a cat and shine!
猫になって開拓するよ
I want to become a cat and pioneer!
もっと君に伝わりますように
May it reach you even more.
猫になって甘やかされたいずっと
I want to become a cat and be spoiled forever!
猫になって抱きしめられたいもっと
I want to become a cat and be hugged even more!
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to become a cat and stay in love,
猫になって笑いあおうよ
I want to become a cat and laugh together!
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats even more!
猫ならばいける 君とならばいける
If we're cats, we can do it with you!
みこち、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mikochi, happy birthday!
猫ならばいける歌えて嬉しかった！まったねー！
So happy we could sing 'Neko Naraba Ikeru'! See you!
もっとね、あおた、ありがとね！
And thanks a lot, Aota!
みこちっ、お誕生日おめでとーっ！僕こうりーん
Mikochi, happy birthday! I have descended!
おかゆっ！いや・・・全肯定のネコマサおかゆん・・・っ♡
Okayu! No... fully-affirming cat-goddess Okayun...! ♡
よしよし、みこちはライブ頑張ってえらいえらい～い。
There, there, Mikochi worked hard on the live, good girl.
とってもエリートだよぉ。
You're very elite!
えへへ・・エリ～トぉ～？え、そうかなぁ～？
Ehehe... Elite? Eh, is that so?
さっすがおかゆん、わかってくれるんだねぇ～
As expected of Okayun, you understand!
おーけおーけぼくが君の神様になったげる
Okay, okay, I'll become your god.
お願い！お願い！しょうがないなー
Please! Please! Can't be helped.
お願い！お願い！助けておかゆん！
Please! Please! Help me, Okayun!
悩める現代の皆様
Troubled modern folks,
けたたましい時代の只中
Right in the midst of a noisy era,
自分の事さえ愛せない
Unable to even love yourself,
そんなことありませんか？
Isn't there something like that?
誰かに認めてもらいたいな
I want someone to acknowledge me,
何もうまくいかずヤダヤダヤダ
Nothing goes right, no no no!
おーけーおーけー
Okay, okay,
ぼくが君の神様になってあげる
I'll become your god.
Help me!
どうしたの〜？
What's wrong?
Help me!
うんうん
Yeah, yeah.
Help me!
そっかー、大変だねー
I see, that's tough.
Save me!
でもねー
But y'know...
Save me!
大丈夫！
You'll be fine!
ぼくが味方でいるからさ〜
Because I'm on your side~
生きてるだけで満点 (満点！)
Just being alive is a 10/10 (10/10!)
自信持ちなよ全然 (全然！)
Have confidence, absolutely (Absolutely!)
信じていいよ当然 (当然！)
It's natural to believe in it (Naturally!)
君はとっても素敵だよ！
You are so wonderful!
ありとあらゆる この世の全てを
Every single thing in this world...
肯定！肯定！全知全能全肯定！
Affirm! Affirm! Omniscient and omnipotent total affirmation!
それって結構、神じゃない？
Isn't that pretty much being a god?
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん (すごーい！)
That's great, that's awesome (So awesome!)
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん (えらーい！)
That's good, that's amazing (Brilliant!)
そうです そうです もっと自由に 生きていいんだよ 全肯定
That's right, that's right, live more freely, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん (すごーい！)
That's great, that's awesome (So awesome!)
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん (えらーい！)
That's good, that's amazing (Brilliant!)
おーけーおーけー 君は最高
Okay, okay, you are the best,
何度だって伝えてあげる
I'll tell you as many times as it takes.
お願い！お願い！しょうがないなー
Please! Please! Can't be helped~
お願い！お願い！たすけておかゆん！
Please! Please! Help me, Okayu-n!
承認欲求 マウント社会 マイナス思考に自己否定
Approval desire, one-upmanship society, negative thinking, self-rejection,
誰もがみんな求め続ける 自分だけにある特別感
Everyone keeps searching for a sense of specialness unique to themselves,
数値化されちゃう世知辛い時代 いいね フォロワー 高評価
In a harsh quantified era of likes, followers, and high ratings.
そんなの全然必要ないよ
You don't need any of that at all.
“ぼくの言葉に全て委ねて”
“Entrust everything to my words.”
あーね！いいじゃん！うんうん！えらーい！おー！かんぺき！きょうもおつかれ！
Ah, right! That's good! Yeah! Great! Oh! Perfect! Good job today!
グッド！けっこう！こうてい！こうてい！
Good! Pretty good! Affirmation! Affirmation!
さすが！じしんもって！ (おかゆん！)
As expected! Have confidence! (Okayu-n!)
すばらしい！せかいいち！そばにいるよ！
Wonderful! World's best! I'm right by your side!
だいすき！ちょうすき！つまりすき！
Love you! Super love you! In short, I love you!
できるよ！とうぜん！なんとかなるよ！
You can do it! Naturally! It'll somehow work out!
にっこり！ぬくぬく！ねこかわいがり！
Smiling! Warm and cozy! Pampered like a cat!
神様も人様もなにもかもも信じられなくても
Even if you can't believe in gods, people, or anything at all,
猫様を信じましょう 甘えましょう 与えましょう 安心
Let's believe in Neko-sama, let's pamper, let's give peace of mind,
晴れの日も雨の日も 支えましょう 君の心を
On sunny days and rainy days, let's support your heart,
病める時 泣ける時 ここに来たならもう大丈夫
When you're sick or crying, once you come here, you'll be fine.
(Help me!) はいはい
(Help me!) Yes, yes,
(Help me!) よしよし
(Help me!) There, there,
(Help me!) うんうん、心配しないで
(Help me!) Yeah, yeah, don't worry,
(Save me!) ほらね
(Save me!) See?
(Save me!) 大丈夫！
(Save me!) You're fine!
君もレッツおにぎりゃー！
You too, let's Onigirya!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん (すごーい！)
That's great, that's awesome (So awesome!)
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん (えらーい！)
That's good, that's amazing (Brilliant!)
そうです そうです もっとぼくの側においでよ 全肯定
That's right, that's right, come closer to my side, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん (すごーい！)
That's great, that's awesome (So awesome!)
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん (えらーい!)
That's good, that's amazing (Brilliant!)
おーけーおーけー ぼくが君の猫様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become your Neko-sama.
のんびりいこうよ ばっちりピカイチ
Let's take it easy, perfectly top-notch,
ファンタスティック へっちゃらポジティブ
Fantastic, carefree and positive.
まあまあみんな無理しないでね めっちゃ心配だよ
Now, now everyone, don't push yourselves, I'm super worried,
(おかゆん！) もぐもぐ！やっぱり！ゆうきの！よっしゃいくぞ！
(Okayu-n!) Munch munch! As expected! Courage's! Let's go!
肯定！肯定！肯定！肯定 全知全能 全肯定！
Affirm! Affirm! Affirm! Affirm! Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん
That's great, that's awesome / That's good, that's amazing
さぁさぁ 皆さん ご唱和ください！ 全知全能全肯定！
Now everyone, please sing along! Omniscient, omnipotent, total affirmation!
いいじゃん いいじゃん すごいじゃん (すごーい！)
That's great, that's awesome (So awesome!)
いいじゃん いいじゃん えらいじゃん (えらーい！)
That's good, that's amazing (Brilliant!)
おーけーおーけー 新世界の 神様になってあげる
Okay, okay, I'll become the god of a new world.
お願い！お願い！らくにいこうよ
Please! Please! Let's take it easy
お願い！お願い！りょこう！るんるん！
Please! Please! Trip! Fun-fun!
お願い！お願い！レッツゴー！ろうろう！
Please! Please! Let's go! Raw-raw!
お願い！お願い！わらってこ
Please! Please! Smile on
みこち！お誕生日 おめでとう！
Mikochi! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
またねー！
See you later!
み、みこちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう…
Mi-Mikochi, happy birthday...
あくたん！ありがとぁ〜！なんでそんな端っこにいるの？ あくたんオオトリだよ！ほら、おいで〜！
Akutan! Thanks so much~! Why are you standing way over there? Akutan is the grand finale! Come here~!
も、もぉしょーがないなぁ… み、みこちゃんもしかしてあたしのことすきすぎ…？照
S-So it can't be helped... M-Mikochi, could it be you like me way too much...? *blush*
よーーし！いくぞーー！
Alriiight! Let's goーー!
えっ、あっ、あれえ…？
Eh? Ah, huh...?
あいわな
Ai Wana
みゅーじっく
Music!
月曜日は体が動きません
On Mondays, my body won't move.
ってゆーか毎日でした。
And I mean, every single day...
ピリピリ偏頭痛
throbbing tension headache.
あたしったら
As for me,
メイドのくせしてお料理ダメ
a maid who's terrible at cooking,
掃除もちょっとアレ
and a bit clumsy at cleaning too.
てんてこ舞いで まいったうん
I'm totally flustered and overwhelmed, yeah.
精進あるのみですね
Guess all I can do is strive harder!
会いたくなってしまったな 今夜も
I've grown to miss you again tonight...
夜な夜な集まって何する？
Gathering night after night, what do we do?
月火水木金土日 365日
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun, 365 days.
画面越し ご挨拶 せーのっ
A greeting through the screen, ready, set—
「好き」なんて言っちゃったって
Saying "I love you" out of nowhere...
全然可愛くない
it's not cute at all!
勝手にへこんだって 泣いてみたって全然可愛くない
Sulking and crying on my own is not cute either.
君だって同じ ダメよりの人種です
You're the same, part of the hopeless breed.
そんな優しくして…あたしに気があるのかなっ
Being so kind to me... could you be into me?
どんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング
What time? What premonition? Divine happening!
阿鼻地獄少女 挑んでマックス メンタルはーがい
Pandemonium girl, max challenge, mental breakdown!
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい
I want to know more and more about you.
あいわな
I wanna...
みゅーじっく
Music!
水曜日は意識がレボリューション
Wednesdays are an ideological revolution.
ってゆーか毎日でした。
And I mean, every single day...
ピリピリ偏頭痛
throbbing tension headache.
あたしったら
As for me,
競争社会不適合者？ でも挙動は適合者…
Unfit for society? Yet my behavior fits right in...
のふりして暴言はいって へこんだ。これって放送事故？
Insults and depression. Is this a broadcast disaster?
会いたくなってしまったな 今夜も 自己嫌悪からの脱却
Missing you tonight, breaking free from self-loathing.
悪霊退散成敗だ 魔法陣なんとか
Exorcising evil spirits, magical circle stuff!
頑張れ私負けるな！ せーのっ
Do your best, don't lose, me! Ready, set—
「好き」なんて言っちゃったって
Saying "I love you" out of nowhere...
全然可愛くない
it's not cute at all!
勝手にへこんだって 泣いてみたって全然可愛くない
Sulking and crying on my own is not cute either.
君だって同じ ダメよりの人種です
You're the same, part of the hopeless breed.
そんな優しくして…あたしに気があるのかなっ
Being so kind... could you be into me?
どんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング
What time? What premonition? Divine happening!
阿鼻地獄少女 挑んでマックス メンタルはーがい
Pandemonium girl, max challenge, mental breakdown!
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい
I want to know more and more about you.
ああ 特別じゃない 私のこと勘違いして…
Ah, nothing special... misunderstand things about me...
馬鹿ね。なれあいこそが君と僕を繋ぐ光
You fool. Familiarity is the light connecting us.
月火水木金土日 365日
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun, 365 days.
画面越し ご挨拶 にゃっはろー！
A greeting through the screen, Nyahallo!
「好き」なんて言っちゃったって
Saying "I love you" out of nowhere...
全然可愛くない
it's not cute at all!
勝手にへこんだって 泣いてみたって全然可愛くない
Sulking and crying on my own is not cute either.
君だって同じ ダメよりの人種です
You're the same, part of the hopeless breed.
どんなに優しくするの…私のこと好きなの？ 確定！
How kind can you be... do you like me? Confirmed!
どんな時間 どんな予感 神ハプニング
What time? What premonition? Divine happening!
阿鼻地獄少女 挑んでマックス メンタルはーがい
Pandemonium girl, max challenge, mental breakdown!
あなたのことをもっともっと知りたい あなたのことを何にも知らない
I want to know more, I know nothing about you.
Kiss me baby
みこちゃん、誕生日おめでとう！ ありがとうございます！
Miko-chan, happy birthday! Thank you very much!
帰るの早っ
You're leaving so fast!
はーーい！みんなゲストパートどうだった？そして新衣装をお披露目しました、どーう？
Hiii! How was the guest part? And my new outfit, how is it?
かわいい？ えへへへ。あのね、ちょっとね、今回はデート服風にあの今回にしました。きゅるるん、きゅん！
Cute? Ehehe. I went with a date-outfit vibe this time. Kyururun, kyun!
これはもう完全にきゅんきゅんですね。はい、みんなスクショしていいよ。はい、はっはっはっは。
This is totally kyunkyun! Feel free to take screenshots. Haha!
とゆーことで残すところあと1曲となりました！が、その前に告知をしたいと思います。
Down to just one song left! But before that, an announcement.
まずはこちら！さくらみこ誕生日記念2024 フルセットはこちらとなります。はーい！
First is this! The Sakura Miko Birthday Commemoration 2024 Full Set. Yay!
いや、とってもかわいいですね！それでは単品を見ていきましょう、まずはこちら！
Man, it's super cute! Let's check the individual items, starting here!
みこちと3Pの記念写真アクリルジオラマスタンド！イラストは、おるだんてんてに描いていただきました！ありがとう！
Acrylic Diorama Stand illustrated by Orudan-sensei! Thank you!
おもにきゅ、きゅんポーズですね、しております。あと、みこぴーもね、ぷぷぷっといつものように折りますね。はい。
Doing the kyun pose. And Miko-p is folding up cute as usual, yep.
では続いて、こちら！3Pふわふわキーホルダー
Now moving on to this! 3P Fluffy Keychain.
のだ！もみこぴーがね、
Miko-pi is...
とってももふもふとなっております。
super fluffy now!
そしてこの金の金具のところはね、
And for the gold metal clasp part,
この新章のこのハートのマークになっています。
it's shaped like this new chapter heart mark!
新章要素が入ってます。かわいい！
New chapter elements are included. So cute!
はい、では続いては…じゃどん！
Alright, next is... Ta-da!
2WAY痛バッグ for 35P！みこぴー用の痛バッグができましたー！
2WAY Ita Bag for 35P! The Miko-pi ita bag is done!
さっきのね、ふわふわのみこぴーをつけたりだとか、あとポケットにはね、あの、みこぴーのぬいぐるみが2匹ぐらい入る大きさととなっております。
You can attach the fluffy Miko-pi from earlier, and the pocket is big enough to fit about two Miko-pi plushies.
ま、あとは缶バッチとかね、いろんなみこのグッズを入れてアピールしてください。2WAYなのでね、リュックにもなります。
And you can put various Miko goods like badges in it to show them off. Since it's 2WAY, it can also be a backpack.
あとまあ、誕生日月同じ、誕生日月の誰かとお揃いかもな、わかんないけど。匂わせおしときます。
Also, maybe it matches someone with the same birth month? I don't know, I'll just leave that hint here.
はい、では続いては こちら！
Alright, next is this one!
35Pキャップ！
35P Cap!
もうとってもね、おしゃれになっております。コーデュロイ生地っていうのがよくわかんない。あの、おしゃれな生地です。
It's super stylish. I don't really know what corduroy fabric is, but it's stylish fabric!
そして、まあ、あの、みこぴーの服のマーク付いたりとか、みこぴーの尻尾の炎が後ろに刺繍されております。おしゃれ！
And, well, Miko-pi's clothing mark is on it, and Miko-pi's tail flame is embroidered on the back. Stylish!
ぜひね、イベントに付けてきてね！
Be sure to wear it to events!
はい、そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full-set purchase bonus is right here!
おるだん先生の、あの、みこの表情差分のイラストに、直筆メッセージと箔押し複製サインが入っております。こちらが数量限定となっております。
It features an illustration with different facial expressions by Ordan-sensei, with a handwritten message and foil-stamped duplicate signature. This is in limited quantity!
みんなね、急いで、頑張って購入してください。
Everyone, hurry up and do your best to purchase it.
よろしくお願いします(笑)
Please look forward to it.
そして、あのね、誕生日記念フルセットにはちゃんとこちらもね、あの、複製のサインとメッセージが入っておりますので、みんな買えないがしてでもぜひね、諦めないで、あの、ぜひ全部ゲットして欲しいなと思います。
And also, the birthday commemorative full set also includes the duplicate signature and message, so even if you can't buy it right away, please don't give up and try to get everything!
そしてフルセット共通特典ボイスも付いてきます！みことみこぴーの星の蜜デートボイスドラマ。ちょっとね、みずらいしいんですけど、ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど、まあ、デート衣装なんでね、みんなぜひ買って聞いてください！
And the full-set common bonus voice drama is also included! Miko and Miko-pi's Starry Honey Date Voice Drama. It's a bit unusual, and a bit embarrassing, but since it's a date outfit, everyone please buy it and listen!
続いてのお知らせは、こちら！鳴門鯛焼本舗さんとのコラボも実施中です！今月末までです。みんな食べに行ってみてね！
The next announcement is this! The collaboration with Naruto Taiyaki Honpo is also underway! Until the end of this month. Everyone go check it out and eat!
はい、ということで、まだもう一つ告知があります。
Alright, with that, there is one more announcement.
この後、新曲をお披露目します！いえい！
Afterwards, I will premiere my new song! Yay!
作詞作曲はキノシタさんにお願いしました！
I asked Kinoshita-san for the lyrics and music!
この後MVのプレミア公開もあります！ぜひ見てね！
Afterwards, there's also a premiere of the MV! Be sure to watch it!
さらに、そのあとはメンバーシップ限定のライブ＆撮影会もあるので、みんなメンバーさんになってね！
Furthermore, after that, there's a membership-only live and photo session, so everyone become members!
あ、なってね！よろしくね、桜組になっていいんだよ！
Ah, become one! Please, it's totally fine to become a Sakura-gumi!
はい、それでは、お待たせいたしました！最後の曲になります。
Alright then, thanks for waiting! It's time for the final song.
それでは聞いてください、新曲「きゅんきゅんみこきゅん」！
So please listen to the new song, "Kyun Kyun Miko Kyun"!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！？
Kyun kyun Miko kyun?!
(きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！)
(Kyun kyun Miko kyun!)
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！
Kyun kyun Miko kyun! Kyun kyun Miko kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん！
Kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！きゅんきゅんみこきゅん！
Kyun kyun Miko kyun! Kyun kyun Miko kyun!
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅんきみねみこきゅん？
Kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun, Miko kyun to you?
あのね、これガチ
You know, this is for real,
みんなトモダチ
everyone is a friend
夢見ルカタチ
the shape of our dreams
でっかいぞってマジ！？
is huge, seriously?!
それはすなわち成長中って話し
In other words, it's a story of being in the middle of growth
いろんなワタシ 超見て欲しい！
I want you to super see all kinds of me!
エリートあいさつ！
Elite greeting!
みんなにゃはろ〜！
Everyone, nyahallo~!
エリートスマイル！
Elite smile!
ふふふ…きりん☆
Fufufu... kirin☆
エリートダンス！
Elite dance!
みーみーみこみこっ！
Mi-mi-mikomiko!
エリートイングリッシュ！I'll be back!
Elite English! I'll be back!
まあね時にはね落ち込んじゃうこともあるよ
Well, sometimes, nye, there are times when you feel down
そんな時ははなまるあげるね！
At times like that, I'll give you a hanamaru, nye!
おまえらよく聞きーーーい!!!!今日も一日よくできました〜！
You guys, listen up real well!!!! Today you did a great job all day~!
はにゃ？ってふにゃってほにゃっと混ぜたら
Hanya? and funya and honyatto mixed together
キュンしちゃうから35チューン(みこきゅん！)
Because it'll make you go kyun, 35 tune (Miko kyun!)
はやっ手ぷにっ手ぽよったらさいきょ----!!!!
Payate, puni-tte, poyottara, saikyo----!!!!
うにゃうにゃしよう？一緒にせーの！
Shall we nya-nya? Together, ready, go!
ドキドキめらめらきゅん！(きゅんきゅん！)
Dokidoki melamela kyun! (Kyun kyun!)
もがもがめらめらきゅん？(きゅんきゅん！)
Mogamoga melamela kyun? (Kyun kyun!)
きらきらめらめらきゅん！(きゅんきゅん！)
Kirakira melamela kyun! (Kyun kyun!)
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅん！
Kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun!
きみにきゅんあげるよ
I'll give you kyun!
ねね！あのねこれガチ
"Hey! You know, this is for real,"
ほっぺはもちもち
"my cheeks are super soft!"
ミライのみちしるべっ！まじーっ！？
"My future guide! Seriously?!"
それはすなわち進行中って話
"That means we're still growing up,"
それは必見だし超見て欲しいっ！
"so it's a must-see, I want you to watch closely!"
エリート拍手！パチパチパチパチ
"Elite applause! Clap, clap, clap, clap"
エリートジャンプ！ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん
"Elite jump! Pyon, pyon, pyon, pyon"
エリートおねね！むにゃむにゃむにゃ…
"Elite big sister! Munya, munya, munya..."
エリートわがまま！やだやだやだ！
"Elite selfishness! No, no, no!"
だっていつだってありのままを伝えたいのに…
"Because I always want to convey my true self..."
おまえらさ、みこをなめてんじゃねー！！
"You guys, don't underestimate Miko!!"
ふざけんなでねぞっ…て言えって言われましたーっ！！
"Don't mess with me... is what I was told to say!!"
ほにゃってふにゃってほにゃっと混ぜたら
"If you mix a little honya and funya,"
キュンしちゃうから35チューン
"you'll fall in love with this 35 Tune"
ぱやっってぷぴっってぽよっったらさいきょうーーーっ！！
"If you go paya, pupi, poyo, it's the strongest!"
うにゃうにゃしてもいいじゃない？せーのっ
"Is it okay to go unya-unya? Ready, set—"
ぴかぴかめろめろきゅんっ！
"Shiny, melting kyun!"
ふわふわめろめろきゅんっ？
"Fluffy, melting kyun?"
みんなみんなめろめろきゅんっ！
"Everyone, melting kyun!"
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅんっ！キミにきゅんをあげるよ
"Kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun! I'll give my kyun to you"
この今が宝物
"This present moment is a treasure,"
いつも愛をありがとう。
"thank you always for your love."
ここからはねみこのターン！ついてきてね！
"From here on out is Miko's turn! Follow along!"
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
"Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!"
うーー！いぇーーい！！
"Ugh! Yay!!"
いつまでもいつまでもずーっとずーっと笑顔でいようね
"Forever and ever, always and always, let's keep smiling"
みこ頑張るよ！頑張れるよ！
"Miko will do her best! I can do it!"
もっともっときゅんきゅんになってね！
"Become even more kyun-kyun!"
ラストにもう一回張り切って～！
"For the last time, let's give it our all once more~!"
みこちゃんは？エリートです！！
"Who is Miko-chan? She's elite!!"
ほにゃってふにゃってほにゃっと混ぜたら
"If you mix a little honya and funya,"
キュンしちゃうから35チューン
"you'll fall in love with this 35 Tune"
ぽやってぷぴってぽよったらさいきょうーーーっ！！
"If you go poya, pupi, poyo, it's the strongest!"
うにゃうにゃしてもいいじゃない？せーのっ
"Is it okay to go unya-unya? Ready, set—"
どきどきめろめろきゅんっ！
"Thumping, melting kyun!"
ぴょこぴょここそめろめろきゅんっ？
"Bouncing, melting kyun?"
きらきらめろめろきゅんっ！
"Sparkling, melting kyun!"
きゅんきゅんみこきゅんきゅんっ！キミにきゅんをあげるよ
"Kyun kyun Miko kyun kyun! I'll give my kyun to you"
みんな～おつみこ～！
"Everyone, good work Miko~!"
そんなときははなまるあげるにゃ！
"At times like that, I'll give you a gold star!"
おまえらよく聞けーー！
"Listen up, you guys!!"
今日も一日よくできました～！
"We did a great job today too~!"
特報！3ヶ月連続リリース決定！！！
[Special Announcement! 3-Month Consecutive Releases Confirmed!]
応援してくれてるみんな♡ありがとう
[Thank you everyone for your support♡]